埃菲姆·曼克考斯基
Ephraim Mankofsky,
或者曼克
Or simply Mank,
他更乐意我们这么称呼他
as he liked to be called,
他的一生都很充实
lived a fruitful life.
作为一名骄傲的父亲
A proud father
他养育了十个优秀的子女
of ten wonderful children...
曼克的生活非常非常的幸福
Mank was so very, very blessed.
这个犹太女孩子是谁
Who's the shiksa?
我想用泡泡糖梦幻色彩指甲油
I'm thinking Bubble Gum fantasy...
或者是爱丽斯磨砂效果的
Or maybe frosted Iris.
我觉得该用大红色  永远是我的第一选择
I'm thinking tickle-the-toe red. It's my go-to color.
来了
Oh.
你等人吗
You expecting someone?
吉娜有几张美容中心的促销赠券
Gina got promotional freebies at a new spa
她邀我们去做美甲
and asked us if we wanted to go get manis,
做做按摩
pedis, and massages.
你竟然也去
And you're going?
亲爱的  牵扯到你前妻的时候
When it comes to your ex-wife, darling,
个人恩怨远没有小福小利来的重要
perks outweigh personal considerations.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hello. - Hello.
-你看上去不错  -谢谢
- You look great. - Well, thank you.
我能去吗
Uh, am I invited?
不行  今天是女生活动日
Uh, no. It's a girls' day out.
我想和玛莎和阿丽克西斯一起聚聚
I want to spend time with Martha and Alexis.
但是我最爱按摩了
Uh, but I love massages,
我也不想你们三个背着我搞密谋
and I don't want the three of you conspiring.
爸  别担心
Don't worry, dad.
我们还有好多其它事情要聊
We've got a lot of other stuff to talk about.
我要听阿丽克西斯新男友的八卦
I want to hear all about Alexis' new boyfriend
从她的角度了解
from her point of view.
你知道他们有自己的歌吗
Did you know that they have a song?
你们有自己的歌
You have a song?
对啊   泰勒·斯威夫特的《我的》
Yeah. Taylor Swift's "Mine."
艾什和我初吻放的就是这首歌
It was playing the first time Ash and I kissed--
啦  啦  啦  啦
La, la, la, la.
我不想听这些
I don't want to hear that.
所以啊  我才特别想要买到票
That's why I wanted those tickets so badly.
泰勒周二有一场个人不插电演唱会
Taylor's playing an exclusive acoustic show on Tuesday,
我很想和艾什一起去
and I wanted to take Ash,
但是我们还没来的及买
but it was sold out
-票就已经售空了  -这样啊
- before we could get tickets. - Well,
你上易趣
have you checked on ebay
或是找你爸认识的那个票贩子了吗
or your father's ticket broker?
能买到的那些票
The only ones available
足够花掉我和艾什两个人六年
would've cost Ash and I six years of allowance...
-是吗  -全部的零花钱了
- Ah, well. - Each.
还记得我们俩的那首歌儿吗
Do you remember our song?
AC/DC的《你令我整夜摇摆》
AC/DC's "You shook me all night long."
-啦  啦  啦  不想听  -天啊
- La, la, la, la. Don't want to hear it. - Ohh.
祝你们玩得愉快
You girls have a great day.
-记住  没我你们不会尽兴的   -不会
- Remember, it won't be the same without me.  - No.
看起来你已经另有安排了
Mm. Looks like you have plans anyway.
不都是调查完被害人才举行葬礼吗
Don't we usually get to the victim before the funeral?
什么情况
What have we got?
吊唁者在棺材里发现一具尸体
Mourners found a body in the casket.
这有什么不正常吗
And that's unusual how?
死者家属正在
Well, the family was bidding
为曼克先生举行遗体告别仪式
a fond farewell to Mr. Mank here,
发现灵柩里面躺着不止他一个人
and discovered that he wasn't going to the grave alone.
是我眼花  还是曼克先生在微笑
Is it just me, or is Mr. Mank smiling?
灵柩里面的另外一个人是薇拉莉·曼洛医生
Our stowaway is Dr. Valerie Monroe,
一名县医院的内科主治医师
An attending internist at county hospital.
是个医生  和死者有什么关系吗
A doctor? Any connection to the deceased?
莱恩正在给家属录口供
Ryan's talking to the family now.
死亡原因
Cause of death?
肝功能衰竭  他喝酒就像喝水一样
Liver failure. He drank like a fish.
我们知道曼克先生的死因
We may know what killed Mr. Mank,
但是这位医生的死因就是个迷了
but your dead doctor here is more of a mystery.
没有枪伤
No bullet holes,
没有刀伤  也没有勒伤痕迹
stab wounds or ligature marks.
她的脖子后面
She has a perimortem bruise
有一处死前造成的瘀伤
on the back of her neck here,
但是这不足以致命
but it wasn't severe enough to have been fatal.
尸斑显示死亡时间
Lividity indicates she died
是昨天晚上七点到九点之间
sometime between 7:00 and 9:00 last night.
但是我要进行尸体解剖
But until I can perform an autopsy,
才能查明死亡的真正原因
cause of death is unknown.
但是很明显
Well, what we do know
有人想要把她的尸体处理掉
is that somebody was trying to get rid of her body.
还有她的钱包和手机
Along with her purse and her phone.
这简直太天才了  竟然想到
You know, it's kind of brilliant when you think about it--
把尸体藏在已经放了死者的灵柩里
Disappearing a body in an already occupied coffin.
而且按照犹太传统
And because Jewish tradition demands
尸体都是要需要马上就入土的
that you bury the body right away,
也就不会被人发现
there's less time to get caught.
如果不是护柩人不小心搞砸了
And if it wasn't for the pallbearers' fumble,
这位医生可就神不知鬼不觉的消失了
the good doctor would've disappeared forever.
好吧  找葬礼负责人谈谈
All right. Talk to the funeral director.
看过去24小时内都有哪些人靠近过灵柩
See if anyone had access to this coffin in the last 24 hours.
我不认识她
I'm telling you, I don't know her.
从来就没见过
I've never seen her before,
我也不知道她怎么会在那棺材里面
and I have no idea how her body got in that casket.
今天早晨我进来的时候
This morning when I came in,
我看到一块后窗玻璃被敲碎了
I found one of my back windows smashed.
你是说有人闯进来
So you're saying somebody broke in here
把尸体塞进了你这里的一个灵柩里
and stashed a body in one of your coffins?
我报警了  但是因为没丢什么东西
I called the police, but since nothing was missing,
你们根本就没现身
you guys didn't bother showing up.
如果当初有人来
Maybe if you had,
我也不用这么麻烦应付曼克夫人了
I wouldn't have Mrs. Manks out for my blood.
据县医院的消息
So according to county hospital,
曼洛医生昨天晚上6点就下班了
Dr. Monroe finished her shift at 6:00 pm last night,
这之后一到两个小时她被杀了
which is about an hour or two before she was murdered,
希望她的同事能告诉我们
so hopefully her colleagues will be able to tell us
那之后她去了哪
where she was headed.
卡塞尔  别玩她的手机了
Castle, stop playing with her phone.
我没玩儿
I wasn't playing.
真的没有  昨天晚上六点以后
I wasn't. The last web searches on her phone
她手机上网的最后记录
were after 6:00 pm yesterday.
她在找纽约州卡托纳市的酒店
She was looking for a hotel in Katonah, New york.
我想这可能和案子有关
I thought it might be relevant.
原来如此
Oh.
再说她手机里有个新出的赛车游戏
She also has the new slot car app,
所以我想她在卡托纳肯定有朋友或者家人
so I'm thinking maybe she has friends or family in Katonah.
或许她在计划密会情人
Or perhaps she was planning a liaison with her lover.
但是被男朋友发现了
Her boyfriend found out,
于是嫉妒难忍杀了她
and killed her in a jealous rage.
尸体上除了脖子后的小瘀伤
Yeah, no visible marks on her body
没有任何明显的创伤
other than a small bruise on the back of her neck--
听起来真有嫉妒火药的味道啊
That sounds like a jealous rage to me.
卡塞尔
Castle.
-你的  -谢谢
- For you. - Oh, yes! Thank you.
你把邮寄地址改到这里了
Are you getting mail here now?
我不想让我闺女看到这个
Only when I don't want my daughter to see it.
你是泰勒·斯威夫的粉丝吗
You're a Taylor Swift fan?
这是给阿丽克西斯的
They're for Alexis.
让我大出血了一回
Cost me an arm and a leg,
但是阿丽克西斯会高兴地跳脚的
but Alexis will be thrilled.
很明显她和艾什有自己的歌
Apparently she and Ash have a song.
是吗  我们也有自己的歌
Yeah? Well, we have a song as well.
-是吗  -对
- We do? - Mm-hmm.
克莱伦斯·卡特的《你是话痨》
"You talk too much" by Clarence Carter.
葬礼负责人说的是实话
Hey. Funeral director's story checked out.
确实有人闯了进去
Somebody did break in.
在灵柩或者窗户上
Did you get any foreign prints
发现可疑人的指纹了吗
on the casket or the window?
没有  被三振出局了
Sorry. Struck out.
不过我们还有击球手
But we may have another at bat.
曼洛的经济状况
Dr. Monroe's financials,
我发现了一些情况
and I found something unusual.
几乎每天早晨她都去买咖啡
Almost every morning, she bought coffee--
一个买咖啡的医生  真有够不正常的啊
A doctor who buys coffee? Wow. That is unusual.
要是去离自己住处
It is if the coffee shop
20个街区远的咖啡店呢
is 20 blocks from her apartment.
也许是上班顺路
Maybe it's on her way to work.
不是  完全相反的方向
Nope. Complete opposite direction.
男朋友住在那附近吗
Boyfriend in the neighborhood?
这就去查
On my way to find out.
这下好了  惹到他了
Great. Now he's mad at me.
我在死者的衣服和头发上发现了这个
I found these on the victim's clothes and hair--
灰尼龙
Gray nylon.
-地毯纤维吗  -已经送到实验室去了
- Carpet fibers? - Sent 'em over to the lab
看能不能找出生产商
to see if they could determine the manufacturer.
死因是什么
How about cause of death?
说到这个有意思的就来了
Well, that's where things get a little interesting.
死者头上的瘀伤是钝器所致
The bruise on her head was made with a blunt object.
可能把她打晕了
May have knocked her out,
但如我所推断  这并不是致命伤
But as I suspected, it's not what killed her.
我在她脖子侧面发现了一个注射针孔
I found a needle mark on the side of her neck.
死者被针孔注射过
She was injected with a syringe.
被下毒了吗
She was poisoned?
也不完全是
Not exactly.
凶手用一只空针管
The killer inserted the needle of an empty syringe
扎进了曼洛医生的颈动脉
into Dr. Monroe's carotid artery,
进行注射
then pushed the plunger,
将针管里的气体注入大脑  造成致命的
forcing air directly into the brain, causing a fatal--
-空气栓塞  -给你小红花  卡塞尔
- Air embolism. - Gold star for Castle.
从注射的手法来看
And judging by the skill of the injection,
我判断这是一名专业医务人士所为
I'd say it was done by a medical professional.
有可能是她县医院的一个同事
Like one of her colleagues at county hospital.
看起来有人给她注射了20毫升"死亡之气"
Looks like someone gave her 20 cc's of death.
翻译：东方 千花 深深 小妖
时间轴：零    后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：大卫熊
现在这么烂的医保状况
You know, with the state of health care
患者和家属也承受极大压力
and how stressful this can be for families and for patients,
这么多医务人员活得好好的
I'm surprised that more medical professionals
还真挺奇怪的
aren't killed every day.
是啊  更不要提他们之间的相互背叛
Yeah, not to mention the betrayal,
诱惑和床第之欢
the lust, the bed hopping.
我看《实习医生格蕾》看多了
I've watched enough medical dramas to know
这些医生就是喜欢滚床单
that doctors are notorious for sleeping with each other.
我敢打赌  就我们说话这会儿
I bet, as we speak,
就在这家医院
in this hospital,
就有两个医生正在某个休息室里厮混呢
two doctors are in a break room doing it,
厮混  我的意思是说
and by "It," I mean--
我知道你什么意思  卡塞尔
I know what "It" means, Castle,
那只不过是虚构的
and that is just a fantasy.
80%的医生
Four out of five doctors
更喜欢和自己专业领域以外的人上床
prefer sleeping with someone outside of their profession.
80%吗
Four out of five?
-对头  -那有多少个会喜欢侦探呢
- Mm-hmm. - How many of them like detectives?
我知道的就有一个
One that I know of.
你是说那个机车小子是个医生吗
Whoa. You mean motorcycle boy is a doctor?
那个"男人"好不好  机车男人
"Man," Castle. Motorcycle man.
随便  但是他是个医生吗
Fine, but he's a doctor?
对
Yeah, he is.
切
Huh.
什么专业的  泌尿医师吗
What kind of doctor? Urologist?
直肠病学医师
Proctologist?
别告诉我他是个妇产科医师
Don't tell me he's a gynecologist.
他是个心脏外科医师
He's a cardiac surgeon.
心脏外科医师  那很
Oh. A cardiac surgeon. Wow. That's--
很厉害  是的
Impressive. Yes, it is.
告诉你
In fact,
今天早晨他还给一个人做了紧急搭桥手术
he did an emergency bypass on someone this morning,
救了那个人的命
Saved the patient's life.
你今天早晨做什么了  卡塞尔
What'd you do this morning, Castle?
人家做了华夫饼
Made waffles.
即使病人已经病危  但每次只要看到
A patient could be terminal and would suddenly just smile
曼洛医生走进来就会露出笑容
every time Dr. Monroe walked into a room.
她的死对我们来说是个巨大的损失
It's a huge, huge loss for us.
她有什么家人吗
Did she have any family?
有个兄弟  在圣地亚哥
Uh, a brother, I think, in San Diego.
有男朋友吗
Boyfriend?
她从来没提过
Not that she ever mentioned.
她经常说医院就是她的家
She used to always say that the hospital was her family.
和同事之间有什么摩擦吗
Was there any friction with any of her colleagues?
昨天
Well, yesterday,
就在她下班前
just before the end of her shift,
曼洛和我们的一个护士
Dr. Monroe had a private meeting
单独谈了话
with one of our nurses.
这有什么奇怪的吗
Is that unusual?
这倒没有  但是谈话之后那护士显得很慌张
No, but, the nurse came out of the meeting looking shaken.
我问曼洛医生出了什么事
I asked Dr. Monroe about the meeting,
但是她说那是个人事务
and she said that it was a personal situation
她希望能够及时解决
that she was looking into and trying to solve.
我需要和这名护士谈谈
I'll need to speak with that nurse.
麦克林克护士  当然可以
Nurse McClintock? Of course.
和一名护士有个人事务
Personal situation with a nurse--
你想的和我想的一样吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
很可能不一样
Probably not.
医院里的三角恋爱
Hospital love triangle.
你想想看
Check it out--
我们死去的曼洛医生
our dead Dr. Monroe,
她和医院的某位"美梦先生"打得热火
she's hot and heavy with her manly Mcdreamy,
直到她在值班室里面撞见自己的情人
until she catches him in the on-call room
和调皮的护士麦克林克
with his scrubs around his ankles,
搂搂抱抱  享受鱼水之欢
shagging naughty nurse McClintock.
于是这名护士和曼洛医生之间
Then the inevitable catfight ensues
不可避免的爆发了一场女生互殴
between said nurse and Dr. Monroe--
双雌大战  一死决胜负
A catfight to the death.
这个题目简直太好了
Ooh, that's a good title for something.
双雌之死亡大战
"Catfight to the death."
你到底看了多少电视剧
How much tv do you actually watch?
多到我确认
Enough to know
这个麦克林克肯定是个超级辣妹
that this nurse McClintock will probably be super hot.
警官
Detective.
-你找我  -你是
- You wanted to see me. - And you are?
麦克林克护士
Nurse Mcclintock.
想要改下你的推理吗
Care to revise your theory?
和我想的不一样  但是坚决不改
Not what I was expecting, but no,
我坚持自己的推理
I'll stand by it.
你好  格雷格
Hey, Greg.
你好  阿克曼医生
Hey, Dr. Akerman.
有什么可以帮忙的吗
So what can I do for you?
我们是来调查曼洛医生被谋杀一案的
Well, we're here about Dr.Monroe's murder.
是啊  太可怕了
Yeah, it's pretty awful.
我们了解到在她下班前  你曾经和她
We understand that you had a meeting with her
有过私下会面
right before her shift ended last night.
没错  我去见她了
Yeah. I saw her.
我喜欢你头发衬托脸颊的样子
I love the way your hair frames your face.
你总是这样造型的么
Do you always wear it like that?
工作的时候是这样  关于曼洛医生
Uh, for work, yeah, but, uh, so about Dr. Monroe?
嘿  格雷格
Hey, Greg.
嘿  菲尔普斯医生
Hey, Dr. Phelps.
看来你在这里很受欢迎
You seem, uh, pretty popular around here.
但根据我们了解的情况
Though from what we've heard,
你和曼洛医生关系一般
maybe not so much with Dr. Monroe.
你昨晚去见她是因为什么事
What did you meet with her about last night?
真的没事  只是
Nothing, really. It's just,
她觉得我跟她的女住院医生关系太暧昧了
she thought I was too flirty with her female residents.
-不难想像  -友好一点有错吗
- Imagine that. - What's wrong with being friendly?
那么之后发生什么
So what happened afterwards?
我送她到救护车停车场
I walked her to the ambulance dock
而且保证和她的住院医生保持距离
and promised to keep my distance from her residents.
她说了声谢谢  就跟一个
She thanked me, and then headed off
我没见过的男人走了
with some guy I'd never seen before.
那么你送曼洛医生离开
Hmm. So you walked Dr. Monroe out
就刚好碰见了某个神秘男子
and then conveniently saw her with some mystery man.
-这就是事实经过  -是嘛
- That's what happened. - Oh.
你昨晚七点到九点在哪里
Where were you last night between 7:00 and 9:00?
你是在问我的不在场证据吗
Are you asking for my alibi?
-认真的吗  -认真的
- Seriously? - Seriously.
-真的吗  -真的
-真的  -真的
- Seriously? - Seriously.
好吧  呃  我
Okay. Uh, I was...
和伊马妮去喝咖啡
Getting coffee with Imani.
我是说菲尔普斯医生
I mean, Dr. Phelps.
不  等等
Uh-- no, wait.
我那时候是跟朗达在一起
At that time, I was with Rhonda--
就是柴姆斯医生
Dr. Chimes.
你可以去问她  她能证实我的去处
You can ask her. She'll verify where I was.
朗达·柴姆斯医生  顺便说一句  性感惹火
Dr. Rhonda Chimes, who's smokin' hot, by the way,
证实了他的不在场证明
confirms his story.
她不断地夸格雷格倾听她的心声
She went on and on about how Greg's such a great listener
还送她那些可爱的小礼物
and brings her all these cute "Thinking of you" gifts.
我就知道
Well, I knew
我的医院三角恋谋杀动机理论是成立的
my "Homicidal hospital love triangle" theory had weight.
格雷格是美梦先生
That makes Greg Mcdreamy.
我也是这样想的  但柴姆斯医生说
See, that's what I thought, but dr. Chimes says
他们的关系完全是柏拉图式的
the relationship was strictly platonic.
于是我询问了更多的员工
So I spoke to more members of the staff,
然后我就发现了其他人
and that's when I found the others.
其他人
"The others"?
这些女人被我称作
The other women in what I call...
格雷格星系
The galaxy of Greg.
每一个女人都围着格雷格转
Each one of these women orbits Greg
认为他是她们的特别好友
and considers him to be their special friend.
这下他就变成种马先生了
Well, that totally makes him Mcsteamy.
不  我跟星系里的所有行星谈过
Nope. Spoke with all the planets in the galaxy,
没有人跟他发生过关系
And none of them are sleeping with him.
而且鉴证组已经检查过整个医院
And CSU did a sweep of the facility.
没有任何一处地毯与他们
None of their carpeting matches the fibers
在尸体上找到的纤维相符合
They found from the body.
不  这没道理
No, makes no sense.
如果你不是为了和她们上床
Why spend all that time listening to women and buying them things
为什么还要听她们诉苦和给她们买礼物
if you're not gonna try and sleep with them?
-贝克特在这里  -也许格雷格是同性恋
- Beckett's here. - Maybe Greg is gay.
从他和我调情的情况看  他不是
With the way he was hitting on me? No. He's so not gay.
他一定是在策划些什么或者有什么秘密
Well, he's working an angle or he's hiding something.
他不是唯一有秘密的人
He's not the only one.
被害人的学生贷款
Our victim's student loans.
从医学院毕业之后
Since graduating med school,
曼洛医生一直以最低限额支付
Dr. Monroe has been regularly making minimum-amount payments
她的44万美元学生贷款
on her $440,000 student loan.
当个医生要花这么多钱吗
That's how much it costs to become a doctor?
还好我做了警察
Glad I became a cop.
然后在医院没有加薪的情况下
And without any increase in pay at the hospital,
六个月前  她开始每周还一万块
6 months ago, she started paying $10,000 a week.
一个月四万块
40 grand a month?
知道那些钱怎么来的吗
Any idea where the money was coming from?
不是从银行账户里的  有人汇款给她
Not from a bank account. From money orders.
就是说有人在帮她还债
So someone was making the payments on her behalf.
刚收到医院保安部的传真
Just got a fax from hospital security.
他们在救护车停车场的监视器拍到这个
They got this off the ambulance dock camera.
格雷格说的是真的
Your boy Greg was telling the truth.
曼洛医生的确跟其他男人走了
Dr.Monroe did Head out with another guy.
保安向医院的人出示了这张照片
Security showed this photo around,
但没人认出这个男人
but no one recognized him.
不管这男人是谁  他可能是曼洛医生
Well, whoever this man is, he might have been
遇害前见到的最后一个人
the last one to see Dr. Monroe alive.
他是凶手的话  肯定是最后一个
Especially if he killed her.
我回来了  猜猜我
I'm home, and guess what I've--
-老爸  吉娜搞到了泰勒的演唱会门票   -什么
- Dad, Gina got tickets for Taylor Swift! - What?
在前排中间  而且还有后台通行证
They're front row, center, and come with backstage passes.
-我们能当面见到她了  -太棒了
- We're going to meet her. - That's great.
我们刚给她的自传开个价  这没什么
We just made a deal for her autobiography. It's no big deal.
我要打给艾什  他肯定会很兴奋
I gotta call Ash. He's gonna be so excited.
看看你都干了些什么
I can't believe you did that.
什么
What?
我也买了门票
I got tickets.
我是说  你怎么不事先问问我的意见
I mean, you didn't even call me to ask me if it was okay?
我没想过你会反对
I didn't imagine that you would disapprove,
-再说阿丽克西斯很高兴  -这不是重点
- and Alexis was delighted. - No, that's not the point.
不  这不是  重点是
No, it's not. The point is that I was trying
我想让阿丽克西斯开心
to do something nice for Alexis.
但显然你认为我
And apparently, all you can see is that I...
-抢了你做英雄的风头  -那不是
- Stole your hero moment. - That's not--
晚安
Good night.
-查到那个神秘男子了吗  -不  还没有
- Any luck on the mystery guy? - No, sir. Nothing yet.
听着  回家吧  明早再研究
Listen, go on home. You can start fresh in the morning.
呃  不
Uh, no--
-还是别走了  -你去哪了
- I wouldn't leave just yet. - Where you been?
-喝咖啡  -一整天吗
- Getting coffee. - All day?
在曼洛医生去的咖啡馆
At Dr. Monroe's coffee shop.
就在费尔克洛斯酒店的旁边
Turns out it's right next to the Faircross Hotel.
-我给经理看了曼洛医生的照片  -然后呢
- I showed the manager Dr. Monroe's picture. - And?
有发现  每周有几晚
Pay dirt. Several nights a week...
我们的被害人都会在
Our victim was spending the night in a suite
一间长期租用的套房里过夜
belonging to a permanent resident--
-房主塞萨尔·卡德隆  -那个大毒枭
- one Cesar Calderon. - The drug lord?
他们叫他el diablo  意思是魔鬼
Mm-hmm. They call him el diablo, the devil.
他们说卡德隆在八十年代掌控
They say Calderon was responsible
市场上一半的可卡因交易
for half the coke on the streets in the '80s,
但他势力过于强大  没人能碰他
But he was so big, no one could touch him.
那么我们神圣的医生
So what was our saint of a doctor
为什么会跟大毒枭一起过夜
doing spending the night with a drug lord?
深夜暗访  神秘的金钱援助
Nightly visits, mystery cash gifts--
听上去薇拉莉·曼洛是魔鬼的情妇啊
Sounds like Valerie Monroe was the devil's mistress.
知名罪犯住在时髦的酒店
A known criminal living in a swanky hotel.
很有阿尔·卡彭的风格
very Al Capone.
一位遇害的情妇
A murdered mistress,
一个残暴的哥伦比亚大毒枭
a brutal Columbian drug lord--
你怎么想的  竞争对手的复仇
What do you think, revenge from a rival cartel,
毒品交易出了岔子
A drug deal gone wrong?
或许谋杀是卡德隆表达
Maybe murder is simply Calderon's way of saying
-"我没那么喜欢你"的方法  -我不晓得
- "I'm just not that into you." - I don't know.
空气栓塞可不像是大毒枭的谋杀手法
An air embolism doesn't exactly strike me like a drug lord's MO.
除非
Unless...
卡德隆故意这样做
Calderon did that on purpose
令嫌疑指向医院员工
to throw suspicion towards the hospital staff
以防尸体被发现  自己受到牵连
on the off chance the body was found.
我不明白的是为什么受人敬重的医生
The thing I don't get is how a respected doctor
愿意和臭名远扬的大毒枭搞在一起
could literally get into bed with a known drug lord.
男人不坏女人不爱嘛
Ah, ladies love the bad boys.
"魔鬼"塞萨尔·卡德隆  终极坏男人
Cesar "El diablo" Calderon... ultimate bad boy.
谁知道我们即将踏入的
I mean, who knows what kind of twisted, depraved,
是一个怎样扭曲  堕落  邪恶的世界
unholy world we're about to step into.
先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Sir, I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
他是理查德·卡塞尔
This is Richard Castle.
我们找塞萨尔·卡德隆
We need to speak with Cesar Calderon.
对不起  我想你们找错房间了
I'm sorry. I think you have the wrong room.
我不认识什么
I don't know anyone named--
理查德·卡塞尔  著名的理查德·卡塞尔吗
Richard Castle? The Richard Castle?
让他们进来  马诺罗  让他们进来
Let them come, Manolo. Let 'em in.
欢迎  欢迎
Welcome. Welcome.
卡德隆先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Calderon, I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
很高兴见到你  而你  不用介绍
Pleasure. And you, sir, need no introduction.
我是你小说的超级仰慕者
I am a huge admirer of your fictions.
只要是我想回顾自己"驰骋沙场"的时光
Whenever I desire a taste of my old, grittier life,
我就会拜读你的小说
I call upon your works.
我最喜欢的是妮基·夫耶戈
My favorite is Nikki Fuego.
什么  你是说妮基·希特
Nikki Fue-- oh, you mean Nikki Heat.
不  我是说妮基·夫耶戈
No, I mean Nikki Fuego.
我只读西班牙译本
I only read the spanish translations.
你读过西语版本吗
Have you read your novels in spanish?
没有
No.
你应该看看  不管什么用西语都会更加精彩
Oh, you should. Everything is better in spanish.
请
Please.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
那么
So...
一个畅销作家
A best-selling novelist
和一位迷人的探长
and a... gorgeous detective
一起来拜访我
have come to pay me a visit.
为什么
Why?
我们在调查一宗谋杀案
We're investigating a murder.
好激动啊  被害人是谁
Ah. How exciting. Who's the victim?
薇拉莉·曼洛医生
Dr. Valerie Monroe.
薇拉莉·曼洛  不
Valerie Monroe? No.
薇拉莉死了
Valerie is dead?
你跟曼洛医生是什么关系
What was your relationship with dr. Monroe?
她...
She, uh...
她是我的
She was my, uh...
我的私人内科医生
My... Private physician.
我心脏不好
I have a bad heart.
六个月前  我心脏病发作
Six months ago, I had a heart attack.
我
My...
我弟弟曼纽尔送我去医院
My brother Manuel took me to the hospital.
薇拉莉当班
Valerie was there, and...
她照顾我
She took care of me.
我给了她一个工作
I offered her a position
做我专人的
as my concierge...
内科医生
Physician.
每周两晚我弟弟照顾我
Two nights a week, my brother is my caregiver.
另外五天薇拉莉照顾我
The other five--Valerie.
这就解释那些钱的来源
That explains the money.
她只是你的医生吗
So she was just your doctor?
不  她是我的
No, she was my--
我的奇迹创造者
My miracle worker.
她令我重新振作
She gave me back my strength.
薇拉莉
Valerie...
让我重新回到这世界
Forced me back into the world.
她让我跟她一起散步
She made me walk beside her.
有时候晚上我们会开车到公园
At night, sometimes we would drive in to the park.
不管是谁杀了她  都要受到惩罚
Whoever did this evil must be punished.
那正是我们要做的  卡德隆先生
We intend to do just that, Mr. Calderon.
昨晚七点到九点你在哪里
Where were you between 7:00 and 9:00 last night?
我就在这里
I was right here.
我订了客房服务
I ordered room service.
酒店员工能证实
The hotel staff can attest to that.
地毯是棕色的  不是灰色
The carpet's brown, not gray.
她不是在这被杀
She wasn't killed here.
你认得这个男人吗
Do you recognize this man?
不
No.
这就是杀她的凶手吗
Is he the one who killed her?
我们只知道她遇害前见过这男人
All we know is that he was with her just before she died.
我之前见过这个人
I've seen this man before.
有几次
A few times,
薇拉莉让我载她到她家附近的餐馆
Valerie had me drop her off at a diner by her place.
有时候这个男人就在那里等她
This man was sometimes waiting.
你记得那家餐馆的名字吗
Do you remember the name of the diner?
服务生说他是午餐常客
The waitstaff said he's a lunch regular,
但他今天还没出现
But he hasn't been in yet today.
他们不知道他的名字
They don't know his name.
或许他杀了曼洛医生  然后潜逃了
Maybe he killed Dr.Monroe and then got outta dodge.
或者吧  我们就在这等
Maybe. Let's just wait here, though.
卡德隆的不在场证明
Calderon's alibi?
酒店员工证实了
The hotel staff confirmed it.
阿丽克西斯喜欢你给的惊喜么
How'd Alexis' surprise go?
结果  吃惊的人是我
Turns out, surprise was on me.
吉娜也给了她门票  前排
Gina got her tickets, too-- front row,
还有后台通行证
backstage access.
怎么听起来酸酸的
You say that like it's a bad thing.
-她应该先跟我商量的  -或许吧
- Well, she should've checked with me first. - Maybe.
但是这至少证明她关心你宝贝女儿啊
But at least it means, she cared enough to do it, right?
就是他
There he is.
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir.
纽约警局  我们有问题要问你
NYPD. We need to ask you a few questions
是关于薇拉莉·曼洛的
about Dr. Valerie Monroe.
你想谈薇拉莉  打给我的办公室
You want talk about Valerie, call my office.
要是你不合作
If you don't cooperate,
我只能逮捕你了
I'm gonna be forced to arrest you.
把枪放下
Hey, drop it!
不  你才要放下枪
No, you drop it.
莱纳德·马洛尼  隶属首席检察官办公室
Leonard Maloney, attorney general's office.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
我们正在调查曼洛医生的谋杀案
We're investigating the murder of Dr. Monroe.
谋杀案  薇拉莉死了吗
Murder? Valerie's dead?
你是怎么认识她的
Exactly how did you know her?
她替我工作
She was working for me...
卧底工作
Undercover.
这就像是阿尔弗雷德·希区柯克电影
It's like an Alfred Hitchcock movie--
美丽的医生
A beautiful professional
秘密潜入内部  给臭名昭著的大毒枭设套
goes undercover to trap an infamous drug lord.
大毒枭
Drug lord?
你的调查对象  塞萨尔·卡德隆
Cesar Caldron--the target of your investigation.
卡德隆  不
Calderon? No.
调查卡德隆可不是我这个级别的调查对象
The investigation of Calderon's way above my pay grade.
再说  他"金盆洗手"好多年了
Besides, he's been out of the drug game for years.
那你的调查对象是谁
Then what was your target?
县医院  州审计长
County hospital. The state comptroller
怀疑他们挪用资金
was investigating misappropriations of funds,
处方欺诈  以及盗窃设备
prescription fraud, and equipment theft.
-医疗欺诈  -我们找不到证据
- Medical fraud?  - And we couldn't find the source,
所以  我让曼洛医生
So, uh, I asked Dr. Monroe
做我们的内部眼线
to be our eyes and ears on the inside.
她找到什么证据了吗
And did she find anything?
没有  但是就在前天
No. And then, uh, the day before yesterday,
她突然打电话给我  要求见面
she calls me out of the blue and wants to meet.
在救护车停靠处
By the ambulance dock.
我到了之后  她说她发现了一些可疑之处
When I got there, she said she was on to something
涉及处方欺诈  可能是个走私团伙
that involved prescription fraud and a possible smuggling ring.
但是  她想等周末去北面
But, uh, she didn't want to point fingers
确认之后再做指证
until she had verified some things up north this weekend.
北面
Up north?
曼洛医生的手机查寻记录  纽约州卡托纳
The searches on Dr. Monroe's phone--Katonah, New York.
走私团伙和卡托纳  有什么关系呢
What does a smuggling ring have to do with katonah?
那儿没什么都没有啊
It's basically a nothing town.
有三个原因让卡托纳出名
Three reasons why Katonah is awesome--
第一  迷人的乡村风景
One, gorgeous countrysides,
第二  那里是《杜恩斯比利》上的漫画家
two, it's where"Doonesbury" cartoonist
加里·特鲁多上学的地方
Garry Trudeau went to school,
第三  也可能是最重要的一点
and three, and perhaps most importantly...
玛莎·斯图尔特住在那儿[商界女强人]
it's where Martha Stewart lives.
你喜欢玛莎·斯图尔特
You like Martha Stewart?
每个人都喜欢她吧
Doesn't everyone?
是的  我很喜欢过
Yeah, I-I liked her,
直到她后来因内幕交易而入狱
until she went to prison for insider trading.
等等  监狱  卡托纳旁边是贝德福德山
Wait a minute. Prison. Next to Katonah is Bedford Hills.
那里面有什么呢  探长
And what's in Bedford Hills, detective?
有个女子监狱
There's a women's prison.
你认为她在怀疑监狱里的某个人
Do you think she suspected someone there?
若要去女子监狱走一趟的话  算我一个
If we're talking about a field trip to a women's prison, I'm in.
淡定  饿狼  听着  给监狱打电话
Easy, tiger. Listen, call the prison,
让他们把过去半年内的到访名单传真过来
have 'em fax over the visitor's log for the past six months
还要一份囚犯名单
and an inmate list.
看是否有人和医院的人或死者有联系
See if anyone there connects to the hospital or our victim.
若是要审查医院工作人员名单
Uh, if we're talking about wading through
和探监记录  我就先撤了
hospital staff lists and prison logs, I'm out.
再说  我还要去谢罪呢
Besides... I've got some amends to make,
必须得贿赂一番才行
and it's gonna take a little bribery.
好了  里克  我来了
Okay, Rick. I'm here.
到底什么事啊
What's so important?
这是干什么
What is this?
我想  一束氢气球
Well, nothing says...
才最能说明
"I'm an ass"
我是个混蛋
like a bunch of helium-filled rubber.
看来这个不起作用了
And you're not smiling.
不
No.
只是
It's just, uh...
我一整天都很郁闷
That I had this sick feeling all day.
我感觉这种争吵的画面似曾相识
I felt like we had had this fight before,
然后我想起了娃娃事件
and then I remembered the doll debacle.
你给阿丽克西斯买了个娃娃作为圣诞礼物
You bought a doll for Alexis for Christmas.
而你已经买了一个
And you already had one
藏在衣橱里  准备给她个惊喜
stashed away in the closet as a surprise.
在她该拿哪个的问题上  我们吵了一架
And it was a battle deciding which one she would keep.
结果你赢了  和往常一样
And you won, like always.
但你买的那个娃娃很恐怖  它的眼睛盯着你看
But yours was so creepy. Its eyes followed you.
我想说的就是这个  里克
This is exactly what I'm talking about, Rick.
即使我们结婚了
Even when we were married,
你还是在阿丽克西斯周围建了围墙
you built a wall around Alexis,
就好像你不想让其他人去亲近她
like you didn't want anyone else to be close to her.
你们两个在一起的时候
When it came to the two of you,
我总像是个旁观者
I was on the outside, looking in.
我只是
I just...
我不想再当一个旁观者了
I don't want to feel like an outsider anymore.
她长大了
She's growing up.
现在还有了男朋友
She has a boyfriend now.
想听听我的感想吗
You want to know the truth?
我觉得我也是个旁观者了
I feel like an outsider, too.
但你说的很对
But you're very right.
以前是我不对
And I was wrong.
这次应该由你来当英雄
And you should be the hero this time.
说得很动听
That's sweet.
你也很体贴
You're sweet.
-早上好  -好
- Hello.  - Yeah.
昨晚谢罪怎样啊
So how did it go with the amends last night?
贿赂成功了吗
Did bribery work?
-贿赂加真诚  -二者结合  永远起效
- That and sincerity.  - Well, it's always a good combination.
是啊  案子怎样了  有进展没
Mm-hmm. How goes the haystack? Any needles?
进展可大了
More like a pitchfork.
根据记录  曼洛医生从未去过监狱
There's no record of Dr. Monroe ever visiting the prison,
但却记录了
but the logs do show
医院的另一名工作人员
that another member of the hospital staff was making
每周定期到贝德福德山监狱探监
weekly visits to Bedford Hills prison facility.
是我们认识的人吗
Anyone we know?
当然认识
Oh, yeah.
格雷格护士  没搞错吧
Nurse Greg, seriously?
千真万确  过去三年
Seriously. For the past three years,
格雷格每周都去看望
Greg has been making weekly visits
一个名叫艾米·波特的女囚犯
to an inmate named Amy Porter,
她在一起未遂的抢劫案中
who is doing 30 years to life
作为逃逸司机背叛入狱30年
for her role as a getaway driver
有个警卫在这次事件中被杀
in a failed robbery where a security guard was killed.
我进一步查了一下
So I did a little bit of digging,
很显然  格雷格在案子审判时
and apparently, Greg was her character
是她的品德证人
witness at her trial.
艾米是格雷格的女朋友
Amy is Greg's girlfriend.
-没错  -曼洛医生在调查
- Mm-hmm.  - Dr. Monroe was on to
处方欺诈以及走私团伙的事
prescription fraud and a smuggling ring.
她认为格雷格从医院偷药品
She thought Greg was stealing meds from the hospital
然后偷运给艾米
and smuggling them into Amy.
让她在监狱里兜售
For her to distribute on the inside.
这么说我猜对了  格雷格的确图谋不轨
So I was right. Greg was working an angle.
他和所有女医生做朋友  是为了利用她们
He was friends with all these women so they would help him.
可能她们都没意识到
Probably without any of them realizing it,
所以我让监狱长去搜艾米的牢房
so I asked the prison warden to go and search Amy's cell
然后把她带到这里来问话
and then bring her down here for questioning.
哟  我刚接到
Yo. I just got off the phone
贝德福德山监狱长的电话
with the warden from bedford hills.
艾米·波特今天早上中风了
Amy Porter suffered a stroke this morning.
-25岁中风  -他们把她送到县医院了
- At 25?  - They sent her to county hospital.
送这儿  为什么不送到
Here? Why not bring her to a hospital
离监狱更近一点的医院呢
a little closer to the prison?
附近有安全病房的只有县医院
Well, county is the nearest hospital with a secured ward.
刚好格雷格也在那儿工作
And that's also where Greg works.
菲尔普斯医生  菲尔普斯医生  听说
Dr. Phelps. Dr. Phelps, we understand
你有一个病人叫艾米·波特
that you're treating a patient named Amy Porter.
是从监狱转来的
She's a prison transfer.
是有过  可惜  她在做磁核共振时死了
I was. Unfortunately, she died while having an M.R.I.
-死了  -尸体在哪儿
- She's dead?  - Where's the body?
格雷格调了包
Greg switched the body.
他不是想在监狱走私非法药品
This wasn't about smuggling something into jail.
而是想从监狱弄个大活人出来
It was about smuggling something out.
格雷格策划了一场越狱
Greg pulled a prison break.
-越狱  -是的  长官
- A prison break?  - Yes, sir.
我们搜索了整个医院  但没找到他们
We swept the hospital, but we didn't find either of them.
看来格雷格既不是美梦先生也不是种马先生
Turns out Greg isn't Mcdreamy or Mcsteamy.
他是诡计先生
He's Mcschemey.
知道他是怎么帮她越狱的吗
Do we know how he pulled this off?
长官  在重新看了证据
Well, sir, after reviewing the evidence,
在帕里什医生的帮助下
and also with Dr. Parish's expertise,
我们大致了解了他的整个计划
we think that we figured it out.
关键就是和那些
The key was forging friendships
能提供文件和药品的女医生建立友好关系
with specific doctors who could provide documents and drugs.
所以他才只陪聊不陪睡
That's why he was just friends and not sleeping with them all.
-他只爱艾米  -在不知情的情况下
- He was committed to Amy the whole time.  - Without knowing it,
格雷格星系的每个女人帮他完成了越狱计划
every woman in the galaxy of helped him with his escape plan--
在死亡证书
Signatures on death certificates,
医嘱和尸体释放通行证上签字
medical orders, body releases.
但他是怎么伪造艾米的死亡的呢
O-okay, but how did he fake Amy's death?
药剂师丽莎·阿克曼给了格雷格一盒
Pharmacist Lissa Akerman gave Greg a container
乙酰基六肽-3
of acetyl hexapeptide-3.
那是种类似肉毒杆菌的药膏
It's a botox-like topical cream,
小剂量使用的话很有效
effective in small doses.
阿克曼以为格雷格是送给他母亲的
Akerman thought it was a gift for Greg's mother,
但格雷格却给了艾米
But Greg instead smuggled it into Amy.
艾米抹了半边脸  暂时让
Amy lathered half her face with it, temporarily diminishing
脸部肌肉功能萎缩
her facial muscles' ability to contract.
伪造出中风的症状
Simulating a stroke.
然后根据监狱规定
And then according to prison protocol,
艾米被送到县医院
Amy was sent to county
接受先进的治疗
to receive advanced medical treatment.
作为一名优秀的医生
And like any good physician,
菲尔普斯立即给她做了磁核共振
Dr. Phelps immediately ordered an M.R.I.
同时格雷格马不停蹄
Kicking Greg's plan into high gear.
格雷格利用了他在急诊室的熟人
Greg used his connections at the E.R.
弄到了吗啡和纳洛酮
to get both morphine and naloxone.
当他把艾米送进磁核共振室时
When he escorted Amy into the M.R.I.,
给她注射了大量的吗啡  使得脉搏减缓
he gave her enough morphine to cause her vital signs to drop
直到仪器感应不到
to where she had no recordable pulse.
从而制造死亡的假象
Creating the illusion of death,
她被下令禁止复苏
and since Amy had a do-not-resuscitate order...
-出自查医生的好意  -她被宣布死亡
- Uh, courtesy of Dr. Zha...  - She was pronounced dead.
格雷格立即把艾米推进了太平间
Not wanting to waste a second, Greg wheels Amy into the morgue.
给她注射了纳洛酮
And then injects her with the naloxone,
-使她恢复过来  -很有《低俗小说》的感觉
- bringing her out of the O.D.  - Very "Pulp fiction."
也很危险  但很奏效
And very dangerous, but effective.
格雷格让太平间管理员
Greg had the morgue supervisor
签了释放尸体所需的所有材料
sign all of the documents necessary to release the body,
然后把无名氏的尸体放在艾米的陈尸袋里
And then placed Jane Doe's body in Amy's bag.
然后像其他情侣一样
Then like any other couple in love,
他们手挽着手走出了医院
they walked arm in arm out of the hospital
踏上了幸福之路
and into the sunrise...
为爱而不惜一切
Risking everything for love.
若忽略曼洛医生被杀一事的话
if it weren't for the fact that Dr. Monroe was killed...
-这算的上是件很浪漫的事了  -慢着
- It'd be a pretty romantic story.  - Hold on now.
格雷格不是有很确凿的不在场证明吗
I thought Greg had a solid alibi for her murder.
长官  我们认为他还有个同谋
Well, Sir, we think that an accomplice was helping him out.
所以我们正在调查他的朋友圈
So we're looking in to known associates,
并派了一队人马到格雷格的公寓
and we've also got a team out at Greg's apartment
去寻找相关线索
looking to see if they can find any leads.
还监控了他的信用卡
We're also monitoring his credit cards,
并且在三州交界处发了全境通告
and we've issued A.P.B.s for the tristate area,
但考虑到他计划的如此周全
but given all of the planning,
他们可能已经有了逃亡之策
they probably already had an escape route planned.
幸运的话  我们可以找到线索
But if we're lucky, we'll catch a break.
线索不就在这吗
I think we just did.
格雷格写给艾米的信  若他们计划已久
Greg's letters to Amy. If they've been planning this
那么信里面应该有线索
for a long time, there's gotta be a clue in the letters.
给格雷格公寓那边的人打电话  若能找到
Call the crew over at Greg's. If we can find
艾米写给格雷格的信的话  就能连起来了
Amy's letters to Greg, then we'll have a full set.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
只是情书而已
These are just love notes.
根本没有关于越狱的信息
There's nothing in here about the escape.
那么我们就把它们当作爱情小说来读
Well, then we have to look at these like a romance novel,
而不是悬疑小说
not a murder mystery.
他们两个将灵魂寄托在这些信中
These people are baring their souls in these letters,
走运的话  可以发现芝华塔尼欧
and if we're lucky, we'll find our Zihuatenjo.
在《肖申克的救赎》里  安迪试着
In "The shawshank redemption," Andy was trying--
不用解释  我知道是什么意思
No, I know what it is.
我是个警察  也看过那部电影
I'm a cop. I've seen the movie.
但是  这里面没有啊
It's just, there's nothing about that in here.
艾米一直在讲她是无辜的
The only thing that Amy talks about is being innocent
她没有犯罪
of the crime she was convicted of
以及她是多么想念格雷格
and how much she misses Greg.
是啊  她亲爱的格雷格也想念她呢
Yeah, it's pretty clear Greg misses her, too.
听听这个  "没有你的日子  度日如年
Listen to this. "The days without you grow longer,
-唯有我对你的爱变得"  -更强烈
- but my love for you grows"...  - Stronger?
更坚硬
"Harder."
好一个诗人啊
A poet he's not.
不是每个人都是畅销罪案小说家
Yeah, well, not everyone is a best-selling crime novelist.
也并不代表着他们的爱就不珍贵
And it doesn't mean that their love was any less.
听听她给他写的
Listen to what she wrote to him.
"我无法忍受看到你受苦
"I can't bear to see you suffer.
再找个人开始新的生活吧
"Make a new life with someone else.
要快乐一点
"Just be happy.
世界上只有你值得拥有幸福"
If anyone deserves it, it's you."
我这里好像有回信
I think I have his response to that.
"我相信的东西不多  但我相信我们的爱"
"I don't believe in much, but I believe in us."
这家伙合我胃口
I like this guy.
"就算有再大的艰难险阻  就算你再努力
"And no matter the obstacles, no matter how hard you try,
你也摆脱不了我  我爱你"
you'll never get rid of me. I love you."
你说的没错  这些毫无用处
You're right. These are worthless.
一对恋人分开三年之后
Uh, so two lovers reunite
再重聚
after three years.
-你会去哪儿  -汽车旅馆
- Where would you go?  - A motel.
不是吧你
Really?
这就是你对"特别"的定义
That's what you call "Special"?
我是假设他们身上没钱嘛
Well, I'm assuming they're on a budget.
好吧  你第一时间会去哪儿
All right, where's the first place you'd go?
不知道  某个浪漫的地方吧
I don't know. Someplace romantic.
也许是有特殊意义的地方
Someplace with special meaning maybe.
比如他们初遇的地方
Like the first place they met?
这里  "我永远不会忘记
Yeah. "I'll never forget
在希尔斯代尔的汉堡波利斯里面
"the first time I laid eyes on you that cold, rainy night
第一次看到你时的那个寒冷的雨夜
inside the burgeropolis in Hillsdale."
新泽西州  希尔斯代尔
Hillsdale, New Jersey.
汉堡波利斯
Burgeropolis?
你认为那儿是他们的宝地
You think that's their special place?
是啊  不可能  那太傻了
Yeah. No, that's... That's stupid.
也许全境通告会有所收获
Maybe we'll get lucky with the A.P.B.s.
随时向我汇报
Well, let me know.
机场  汽车站  火车站都没有消息
Nothing from airports, bus or train stations.
信用卡也没被用过
There's no credit card activity.
显然格雷格在一周前
Apparently Greg pulled all of his money
将所有资金取出来了
out of his bank account a week ago.
8000美元
$8,000.
逃出国境都绰绰有余了
That's more than enough money to get out of the country.
他们可能正在逃往加拿大的途中
They're probably halfway to Canada by now.
那我们把他们的照片送到边境巡逻队
Well, we sent their photos to border patrol,
若他们试图越境  我们就能抓获他们
so if they try to leave, we'll catch 'em.
万一他们躲在朋友的后备箱里呢
Unless they're hidden in the trunk of their buddy's car.
对曼洛医生身上的地毯纤维的检测结果出来了
Lab I.D.'ed those carpet fibers from Dr. Monroe's body.
那是车辆后备箱的内衬
They're from the lining of a car trunk,
是辆帝威  出厂不到五年
A Deville, manufactured within the last five years.
也许同谋就是这样
Well, that's probably how the accomplice
将尸体运到殡仪馆的
got the body to the funeral home.
好的  查一下殡仪馆附近的
All right. Check into surveillance cameras
监视录像
within the vicinity of the funeral home.
没准我们走运  能找到车牌号
Maybe we'll get lucky, get a license plate,
追踪到那个共犯
and track down that accomplice.
直接问格雷格共犯是谁
Or you could just ask Greg
-就可以  -什么
- who his accomplice is.  - Sir?
你派去监视汉堡波利斯的
Those Jersey state troopers
新泽西巡警  刚在车行外卖店
you had staking out the Burgeropolis
拦下了那对在逃情侣
just pulled your fugitive love birds from the drive-thru,
他们在来的路上
and they're bringing 'em in now.
你让新泽西警察监视汉堡波利斯
You had Jersey troopers stake out the Burgeropolis?
-是啊  -但是你说这个地方很蠢的
- Yeah.  - But you said that was stupid.
不对  是你说很蠢的
No, you said it was stupid,
看来你错了
and it looks like you were wrong.
不  不  不  我是对的
No. No, no, I was right.
我爱她
I love her.
我该怎么做  让她在监狱里终老一生吗
What was I supposed to do, leave her in that prison to rot?
是你的话你会怎么做
What would you have done?
你的真爱为了一个莫须有的罪名
The love of your life stuck behind bars
饱受牢狱之苦
for a crime she didn't commit --
这不是重点  麦克林克先生
That's not what this is about, Mr. Mcclintock.
这就是重点
Yes, it is.
艾米没有在那次劫案中驾驶逃窜车辆
Amy didn't drive the getaway car in that robbery.
她的车被偷了  她是被冤枉的
Her car was stolen. She got screwed --
醒醒吧  格雷格
Get focused, Greg.
我们对你女朋友的案子不感兴趣
We're not interested in your girlfriend's crimes.
我们是为了曼洛医生的谋杀案才找你的
We're here because of Dr. Monroe's murder.
什么
What?
我有不在场证明  记得吗
I have an alibi, remember?
我们知道你有不在场证明
We know you have an alibi.
我们还知道你有共犯
We also know that you have an accomplice.
我没有共犯
I don't have an accomplice.
我对她的谋杀案一无所知
I don't know anything about her murder.
是啊  曼洛医生找你就真的是为了
Right. And Dr. Monroe really pulled you into that meeting
指责你跟她的住院医师打情骂俏
to scold you for flirting with her residents.
她怀疑你了  她知道药的事
She was on to you. She knew about the drugs,
她知道你的计划  她知道贝德福德山的事
she knew about the plan, she knew about Bedford Hills,
所以你就杀了她
and that's why you had her killed.
不是的  她把我拉进办公室的时候
No. When she pulled me into her office,
我就知道她怀疑我了
I knew she was on to me.
在她毁掉一切之前
I had to move fast before
-我必须快点行动  -所以你杀了她
- she ruined everything.  - So you killed her.
不  我没杀
No, I didn't kill...
我只是更改了艾米的越狱日期
All I did was change the date of Amy's escape.
我得赶在曼洛医生查出真相之前
I had to get her out
把她救出来
before Dr. Monroe found out everything.
又或者她已经知道真相了
Or maybe she already knew everything.
也许她威胁要举报你
Maybe she threatened to turn you in.
不  从她的问题里
No. From her questions,
我可以看出来她是在套我的话
I could tell she was fishing,
想要将线索串起来
trying to put the pieces together.
她会两天放假  所以我想如果我可以
She was off shift for the next two days, so I figured
引开她的注意  然后离开她的办公室
if I could distract her and get the hell out of her office,
我们的计划也许还是可行的
our plan might still have a chance.
你说引开她的注意是什么意思
What do you mean, you distracted her?
就是换个话题
You know, change the subject.
我开始问她关于她的新手镯的事
I started asking her about this new bracelet she had,
那是她男朋友送她的很珍贵的礼物
how it was a special gift from her boyfriend.
然后几分钟以后
Then a few minutes later,
她的电话响了  我就赶紧离开了
her phone rang, and I got the hell outta there.
故事编的不错
Well, that's a pretty good story.
只不过曼洛医生没有男朋友
Only Dr. Monroe didn't have a boyfriend.
不  我发誓
No, I swear.
就她谈起那个手镯时的神情来看
The way she was talking about that bracelet,
她绝对有男朋友
she definitely had a boyfriend.
在整个调查中
In this whole investigation,
从来没提到过她有男朋友
there has not been one mention of a boyfriend.
那是因为他在说谎  看
Probably because he was lying. Look.
没有  没有  没有
Nothing, nothing, nothing.
看见了吗  没有手镯
See? No bracelet.
离我们推测的死亡时间不久
Nearby bank cam caught a photo of a deville
附近的银行摄像头拍到一辆凯迪拉克帝威
heading towards the direction of our funeral home
开向殡仪馆的方向
shortly after our window for time of death.
这是当晚经过的唯一一辆帝威
It was the only one that passed by that night.
有没有更好的角度
Well, is there a better angle
可以让我们看到
so we could see the license
车牌号或是司机的
plate or the driver?
没了  这是角度最好的一张了
Nope. That's the best one.
看  他没撒谎
Oh, look. He wasn't lying.
她被杀前一晚的确戴着手镯
She was wearing a bracelet right before she was killed.
那手镯去哪了呢
Well, where did it go?
鉴证组没有在棺材里
CSU didn't find one
或是其它任何地方找到手镯
in the coffin or anywhere else.
-被凶手拿走了  -为什么
- The killer took it.  - Why?
看上去也不像是很值钱的样子
I mean, it doesn't look like it was worth very much.
而且要是为了钱的话
And if it was about money,
为什么不拿她的钱包呢
how come he didn't take her purse?
因为这跟钱无关  这是冲动杀人
Because it wasn't about money. It was about passion.
你能认出那个手镯吗
Do you recognize that bracelet?
我见过那个设计
I've seen that design before.
探长  卡塞尔先生
Detective, Mr. Castle,
薇拉莉的谋杀案有进展了吗
have you made any progress finding Valerie's killer?
是的
We believe we have.
说说看  你和曼洛医生
Tell me, what was the exact nature
到底是什么关系
of your relationship with Dr. Monroe?
我已经告诉过你了  她是我的医生
I told you already. She was my physician.
你之前的确是这么说的
You said that before,
但是我搞不懂的是  跟你不同
but I'm confused. You see, unlike you,
我不会和我的医生浪漫地开车出游
I don't take long, romantic drives with my doctor.
那是我和我女朋友才会做的事
I do that with my girlfriend.
我们现在又不是活在旧社会
We don't yet live in a world where passion is a crime,
激情不算犯罪  对吧探长
do we, detective?
的确不是  但是冲动杀人算
No, but crimes of passion are,
尤其是谋杀
especially murder.
你戴的项链很好看  卡德隆先生
That's a lovely necklace you're wearing, Mr. Calderon.
可以给我一下吗
May I?
我注意到这跟薇拉莉
I couldn't help but notice, it bears a similar design
在被杀当晚戴的手镯
to the bracelet that Valerie was wearing
有着相似的设计
the night she was killed.
那是因为手镯是我送给她的
That's because I gave it to her
它象征着我对她的爱慕之情
as a token of my affection.
那是我母亲的手镯
It belonged to my mother.
这项链是我父亲的
This belonged to my father.
它们是一对的
They're a set.
既然是传家宝
Well, considering it's an heirloom,
怪不得你会想要拿回来
no wonder you wanted it back.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
我们发现她尸体的时候  没有找到手镯
It wasn't on her body when she was found.
有人把它拿走了
Someone removed it.
发生什么事了  她拒绝你了吗
What happened? Did she reject you?
于是过去那个的卡德隆回来了
Is that when the old Calderon returned --
不是我们眼前这个
not the, uh,
品好酒  有教养的人
cognac swirling renaissance man we see before us,
而是那个无情的杀手
but the ruthless killer?
小心说话  卡塞尔先生
Careful, Mr. Castle.
这可不是你的小说
This is not one of your fictions
你可以随便写死一个人
where people bleed ink.
是的  我爱她  但是我没有杀她
I loved her, yes. But I did not kill her.
我当晚就在这
I was here.
你有足够的钱买通别人为你作证
And you're wealthy enough to have bought that alibi.
你这么说太过分了
This is outrageous.
我不接受你的诋毁
I will not be slandered.
要是有证据就不是诋毁了
It is not slander if there is proof.
这是她被杀那晚
This is a photo from an ATM camera
在距离她的弃尸地点  也就是殡仪馆
The night that she was killed,
一个半街区左右的一个银行提款机
about a block and a half away from the funeral home
摄像头所拍到的照片
where her body was dumped.
那是你的车  卡德隆先生
That's your car, Mr. Calderon.
就是你和薇拉莉浪漫地驾车游
The same one you and Valerie used
所开的那辆车
to take your long, romantic drives.
不  不  你们搞错了
No, no, you're mistaken --
省省吧  卡德隆
Save it, Calderon.
我们在她的尸体上找到了尼龙纤维
We found nylon fibers on her body --
是灰色的  正好是
gray, just like the color
你的帝威车尾箱内衬的颜色
of the carpet on the back of your deville.
那么她的尸体怎么会
So what was her body doing
被塞在你的车尾箱里呢
stuffed in the trunk of your car?
我当晚就在这  我
I was here. I...
我  我记得
I-I remember the...
我就在这
I was here.
但是你
But you...
你那天晚上拿走了车钥匙
you took the keys that night.
上帝啊
Madre de dios.
是你
Oh, it was you.
我能从你的眼神里看出来  马诺罗
I can see it in your eyes, Manolo.
是你干的
It was you.
你不明白  哥哥
You don't understand, Hermano.
我必须这么做  我是为了你才这么做的
I had to. I did it for you.
-为什么  -她是个线人  塞萨尔
- Why?!  - She was an informant, Cesar.
我在餐厅看到她跟那个男人在一起
When I saw her with that man at the diner,
我就跟踪了他
I followed him.
你知道我发现什么吗
And you know what I found?
他在首席检察官办公室工作的
He worked for the attorney general.
她背叛了你
She betrayed you.
你为什么不来告诉我
Why didn't you come to me?
因为你已经为爱盲目了  哥哥
Because you were too blinded, brother.
当你把母亲的手镯给她的时候
And when you gave her mother's bracelet,
我就知道只有我能阻止薇拉莉伤害你
I knew it was up to me to keep Valerie from hurting you.
你干了什么  马诺罗
What did you do, Manolo?
他打了她的头  把她打晕
He hit her in the head, knocked her out.
然后用他为了照顾你
And then using the syringe skills
而学到的医术  往她的血管里注射了空气
he developed caring for you, he injected her with air.
没有留下任何血液证据
Leaving no blood evidence.
然后把她的尸体塞进了另一个人的棺材
And then he stuffed her body into someone else's coffin
这样你就永远不会知道了
so that you would never know.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do this?
我用你教我的方式
I made them disappear...
让他们消失  哥哥
just like you taught me, Hermano.
没有尸体
No body...
也就没有谋杀
no murder.
曼纽尔·卡德隆
Manuel Calderon, you're under arrest
你因谋杀薇拉莉·曼洛医生被捕
for the murder of Dr. Valerie Monroe.
我不能让她伤害你
I couldn't let her hurt you.
实际上  她不会伤害你哥哥
The fact is, she wasn't going to.
她根本没有在调查你哥哥
She wasn't investigating your brother.
她是在查县医院的贪污案
She was looking into corruption at county hospital.
你白白杀了她
You killed her for nothing.
我们走
Let's go.
那个叫格雷格的护士
You know, that nurse Greg fellow?
他让我印象深刻
He impresses me.
为了将心爱的人救出牢狱
You know, someone willing to risk it all
不惜赔上一切
to break his lover out of the big house.
我们的生命里都应该有那样一个人
We should all have that in our lives.
没错  的确应该
Yeah, we should.
你回来了
Hey! You're home.
演唱会怎么样
How was it?
泰勒棒极了
Taylor was amazing.
她唱到我们的定情曲时
Ash and I held hands
我和艾什一直牵着手
while she sang our song.
简直太棒了
It was so great.
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much.
谢我什么
For what?
别装了
It's okay.
吉娜已经告诉我了  票是你们俩一起买的
Gina told me. The tickets were from both of you.
晚安
Good night.
吉娜真是体贴呀
Very considerate of Gina.
的确  不是吗
Yeah, it was, wasn't it?
你开始喜欢她了  对吧
You're starting to like her, aren't you?
在你高二的时候
I stopped being emotionally invested
把可爱的丽兹甩了以后
in your girlfriends after you dumped
我就不对你的女朋友投入任何感情了
that darling Lizzie in eleventh grade.
吉娜还不错
Gina's very nice.
有时候有点过火  但是你知道的
She's a little over the top, but, you know...
你开心我就开心了
You're happy, I'm happy.
但是  问题是
But...the question is this,
到了最后
when you come right down to it,
你会愿意帮她逃狱吗
would you be willing to break her out of prison?
因为孩子
Because that, my boy,
那才是真爱
is true love.
天啊  我爱死你了
Oh, god. I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我无法忍受你为了我也被关起来
I can't stand the thought of you getting locked up over me.
也许不会呢
Well, you might not have to.
你一直坚持说你是清白的
After hearing all your, uh, claims of innocence,
所以我们决定看了一下你的卷宗
we decided to go over your arrest file.
结果发现有很多前后不一致的地方
Turns out, there were a lot of discrepancies.
所以我们把你的档案交给了
So we sent the files to Leonard Maloney
首席检察官办公室的莱纳德·马洛尼
over at the attorney general's office,
他同意我们的看法
and he agreed.
显然你的公设辩护律师是个废物
Apparently your public defender was a real hack.
他忽略了几个关键证据
He overlooked several key pieces of evidence.
包括由于目击证人患有精神疾病
Including a statement that was ignored
而不予采纳的证词
because of the eyewitness' mental illness,
所以马洛尼同意重审你的案子
so Maloney has agreed to reopen your case,
他认为还你清白的几率很大
and he believes that you have cause to be hopeful.
那格雷格呢
What about Greg?
为了维护正义  马洛尼说
Well, in the spirit of justice, Maloney has said
如果你被判无罪了
that if you get exonerated,
他会建议给予格雷格缓刑
he will recommend that Greg gets probation.
你们为什么要做这些
W-why are you doing all this?
因为有人让我相信
Because someone convinced me
像你们这么美好的爱情故事
that a love story as good as yours
应该有个圆满大结局
deserves a shot at a happy ending.
我们觉得很遗憾
We feel bad that the state troopers
因为州警在你们重温第一次约会之前
picked you up at Burgeropolis
就把你们从汉堡波利斯抓来了
before you were able to relive your first date.
所以在你们出狱之前
So until you do get out...
先拿这个凑合着吧
we brought you this.
我叫他们不要放洋葱了
I, uh, told 'em to hold the onions.
你们俩刚才在里面做的事情很感人
That was a nice thing you guys did in there.
我只是觉得在格雷格为她做了这么多之后
Well, I just thought that after everything Greg did for her,
应该给他们一个机会
they deserved a chance.
再说  如果咱俩是艾米的话
Besides, if it were you and I in Amy's shoes,
也许我们还在监狱里等死呢
we'd still be rotting in prison.
那是你  兄弟  我会逃狱的
Speak for yourself, bro. I'd escape.
什么  你就把我一个人扔在里面呀
What, you'd just leave me in there?
这是丛林生存法则
It's the law of the jungle.
我得先为自己着想
I gotta look out for numero uno.
一次假想的监狱之旅
Wow. Nothing like a hypothetical prison term
就让我知道我真正的朋友是谁了
to let you know who your friends really are.
别担心卡塞尔  我会救你出来的
Don't worry, Castle. I'd get you out.
你来吗
You coming?
来了
Yeah.